- Hi everyone, today I'm going to talk
about catalog growth strategy.
I've been selling on Amazon for five years
and I think the most effective catalog growth strategy
actually is prioritizing growing
on your existing hero ASINs.
Say, I have a listing that sells well.
The first thing I would think of
is how do I add more variation to it?
Common variation, which has been very successful for us,
is adding colors.
I can't imagine any product,
couldn't have more than one colors.
Another variation you can add is sizes.
I also can imagine many products
could have different sizes,
even a cup, a plate, a blanket.
So those two variation themes
has been a very successful growth strategy
for us, for our catalog.
And people would ask how many variations
should I add up to?
Wouldn't too many variations make people hard to choose?
I would say that over my experience,
the best, the maximum number of variation
you can add up to would be around 30.
I may be a little biased 'cause I sell in women's fashion.
So color is everything and people love to choose
from many different colors.
For my experience, 20 to 30 variations
is a sweet spot.
Another idea is to add accessories.
So say if I have a shirt,
can I design a pair of pants to match it?
If I have a cup, can I design a plate
to match the same design?
And once you have the new accessories
in a different listings,
then you will bundle them up using Amazon bundle
so then customers could see the matching accessories
within the bundle and increase your total order value.
So those are the few pieces of tips to grow your catalog.
Thank you.